Guide to the William Webster Hansen Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
William Webster Hansen papers
1925-1945
SC0004
Hansen, W. W. (William Webster), 1909-1949
7.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Olive Ross, 1955, and Robert Hofstadter, 1992.
Information about Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Biography
William Webster Hansen was Professor of Physics and Director of the Microwave Laboratory at Stanford University, 1929-1949.
Scope and Content of Collection
Hansen's professional and research papers include correspondence, manuscripts, research notebooks, lecture notes, unpublished studies and notes on various experiments and scientific developments such as radar, the rhumbatron, the klystron, radiation and microwave mechanics. Also included are Hansen's account of the development of the klystron tube, reports of the first linear accelerator at Stanford, his M.I.T. lectures on microwave physics, patents, scrapbooks, and photographs.
Access Terms
Beckerley, James Gwavas.; Hansen, W. W. (William Webster), 1909-1949; Kirkpatrick, Paul.; Massachusetts Institute of Technology.; Morse, Philip M., (Philip McCord), 1903-1985.; Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1904-1967.; Sperry Rand Corporation. Sperry Gyroscope Division.; Stanford University. Department of Physics. -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Webster, David Locke, 1943-; Woodyard, John R.; Cavity resonators.; Klystrons.; Physics--History.; Radar.; Spectrum analysis.
Collection Contents
- ENGINEERING and MECHANICS NOTES, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  lecture notes, problems & exams
- ANALYTICAL MECHANICS, W. W. HANSEN, PHYSICS DEPT. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  probably lecture notes
- PROBLEMS ON MATH, PHYSICS (Box 1, Folder 3)
  collection of problem sets
- "THE RELATION BETWEEN THE CONTINUOUS AND LINE SPECTRA OF X-RAYS FROM THIN TARGETS" By D.L. WEBSTER (DAVID LOCKE) and W.W. HANSEN (Box 1, Folder 4)
  abstract with outline drafted Feb. 14, 1929, calculations, etc.
- "A 10cm SIGNAL GENERATOR" by W. W. HANSEN, EDWARD LEONARD GINZTON, & P. KINNEL (Box 1, Folder 5)
  article and handwritten draft, probably a lecture
- NOTES ON MATRIX THEORY -at M.I.T. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- NOTES ON DIRAC'S THEORY -at M.I.T. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- PROBLEMS IN WOOD'S ADVANCED CALCULUS (Box 1, Folder 8)
- NOTES ON FERMI STATISTICS; also material on Maxwell statistics. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- NOTES ON QUANTUM MECHANICS INCLUDING KRAMER'S ON SPINORS (Box 1, Folder 10)
- NOTES ON MORSE (Box 1, Folder 11)
- VARIOUS PHYSICS COURSES (Box 1, Folder 12)
  lecture notes (?) and exams
- NOTES ON SPECTROSCOPY (Box 2, Folder 13)
- NOTES ON RELATIVITY (Box 2, Folder 14)
  and problems from Physics 239, Spring, 1936
- NOTES ON QUANTUM MECHANICS by WILLIAM VERMILLION HOUSTON (Box 2, Folder 15)
  includes notes, probably lecture, for Physics 206, Wave Mechanics, handwritten apparently by Hansen, various other Hansen material
- QUANTUM MECHANICS. NOTES FROM ROBERT OPPENHEIMER (Box 2, Folder 16)
  handwritten, title indicates source
- NOTES ON BLACK BODY RADIATION FROM EPSTEIN (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Handwritten notes, title indicative of source
- IONIZATION THEORY NOTES FROM WEBSTER (Box 2, Folder 18)
- NOTES TAKEN AT MICHIGAN (Box 2, Folder 19)
- HEAVISIDED CALCULUS (Box 2, Folder 20)
  includes notes entitled: "Solution of Oscillating Currents by the Use of Generalized Angular Velocity", and "Coupled Circuit by the Method of Generalized Angular Velocities."
- GRADUATE EXAMINATIONS (Box 2, Folder 21)
  handwritten, apparently taken by Hansen ca. 1930
- ENGINEERING AND MECHANICS, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  various Physics exams for 1931 and some of Hansen's (probably lecture) notes
- PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY NOTES (Box 2, Folder 23)
  notes on Physical Chem and some exam sheets for Chem 171 (1929) and Chem 173 (1930)
- BROWN'S HEAT LAB. MANUAL (Box 2, Folder 24)
  various notations by Hansen and problem or outline sheet for Physics 34, Heat Lab
- STUDIES FOR GRADUATE EXAMINATION (Box 2, Folder 25)
  notes by Hansen on calculus and physics
- NOTES ON MICROSCOPES FOR MEDICAL OPTICS (Box 3, Folder 26)
- COURSE IN ENGINEERING AND MECHANICS FROM WEBSTER (Box 3, Folder 27)
  some, perhaps all (?) material relates to Physics 215, Spring 1925/26
- COMPLEX VARIABIES (Box 3, Folder 28)
  handwritten and typed notes
- NOTES ON THERMODYNAMICS AND KINETIC THEORY (Box 3, Folder 29)
  probably Hansen's on Physics 211, 1931
- NOTES ON KINETIC THEORY FROM D.L. WEBSTER (Box 3, Folder 30)
  Hansen's on Physics 211
- VARIOUS PATENTS (Box 3, Folder 31)
  German and American, none by Hansen
- PATENTS (Box 3, Folder 32)
  American relating to electronics, copies probably used for reference
- BLIND LANDING ARRAY (Box 3, Folder 33)
  reference to some device on which Hansen was working in connection with Sperry Rand Corp.
- APPLEGATE'S PATENTS (Box 3, Folder 34)
  various patents by L.M. Applegate
- SOME IDEAS ABOUT BALL BEARINGS, Sept. 13, 1944; photostatic copy of handwritten material (Box 3, Folder 35)
- PATENTS BY W.W. HANSEN, VARIAN, SLOAN, SNOW etc. (Box 3, Folder 36)
- REAMER THEORY (Box 3, Folder 37)
  front sheet dated Mar. 18, 1937 is a statement of Hansen's reamer theory; includes various calculations, graphs, etc. all concerned with reamer theory
- DIRECTOR, AIR, CALC. (Box 3, Folder 38)
  various calculations, some involved with ballistics
- MISC. RADAR (Box 3, Folder 39)
  graphs, calculations, data sheets, etc.
- HALF-PLANE DIFFRACTION (Box 4, Folder 40)
  hand-written, entitled: "A New Treatment of the Half-Plane Diffraction Problem"
- SEISMOGRAPH PROBLEM (Box 4, Folder 41)
  handwritten material including calculations, graphs, etc. folder dated Sept., 1936
- SPACE CHARGE IN THE ATMOSPHERE -, undated; handwritten (Box 4, Folder 42)
- APPROXIMATIONS TO BESSEL FUNCTIONS OF HIGH ORDER, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- BRAGG'S LAW (Box 4, Folder 44)
  handwritten, undated material
- WORK ON HELIUM SPECTRUM (Box 4, Folder 45)
  at M.I.T., many graphs etc., handwritten material entitled: "Calculation of the Energy Levels of Helium"
- ATOMIC ENERGY (?) (Box 4, Folder 46)
  various typed and handwritten sheets
- PRELIMINARY WORK ON GREEN'S FUNCTIONS (Box 4, Folder 47)
  typed material entitled: "Abstract" (simple method of finding expansions for Green's Functions occurring in mathematical physics, several new Green's Functions illustrate method), and handwritten material
- REENTRANT SPHERE RESONANCE & ETC., handwritten (Box 4, Folder 48)
- FEED-BACK AMPLIFIERS, handwritten (Box 4, Folder 49)
- LUMPED CONSTANT CALCULATIONS ON RHUMBATRONS (Box 4, Folder 50)
  handwritten, graphs, etc.
- TUNING BY BUMPS (Box 4, Folder 51)
  work done Oct. 1938 by Hansen and D.L. Webster
- IMPEDANCE MATCHING ON RHUMBATRON, handwritten (Box 4, Folder 52)
- CALCULATIONS ON WAVE GUIDES, April 9, 1939; handwritten (Box 4, Folder 53)
- CURRENT DISTRIBUTION PROBLEM -, undated; handwritten (Box 4, Folder 54)
- RADAR ANTENNA THEORY (Box 4, Folder 55)
  handwritten material entitled: "Design of Antennas to Give Prescribed Patterns, Sharp Beams, Focussing by a Cylindrical Lens"
- RADAR: SIGNAL-TO-NOISE, handwritten (Box 4, Folder 56)
- MODIFIED SCHMIDT TELESCOPE, handwritten (Box 4, Folder 57)
- MOTION OF WEIGHT WITH ATTACHED ROPE (Box 4, Folder 58)
  "Sleater's Intergal" is the title (this may be Integral)
- PRELIMINARY CALCULATIONS ON CYLINDRICAL As and CORRESPONDENCE WITH JAMES GWAVA BECKERLY, Summer, 1935; both handwritten and typed (Box 4, Folder 59)
- ANTENNA ARRAYS (Box 5, Folder 60)
  some personal correspondence with Dr. (? H.P.) Westman, 2 abstracts: "A New Principle in Directional Antenna Design" by W.W. Hansen and J.R. Woodyard, original handwritten and typed copy, various other papers and graphs
- PRELIMINARY CALCULATIONS ON DIRECTIONAL EFFECTS AND MS (Box 5, Folder 61)
  handwritten material and a typed abstract entitled: "Radiation from an Antenna Over a Plane Earth of Arbitrary Characteristics" by W.W. Hansen and J.G. Beckerley
- ANTENNA DESIGN (Box 5, Folder 62[R-2])
  photostatic copy, letter between Hansen and Dr. Carl R. Spangenberg of Stanford University dated 1943
- CALCULATIONS ON SPHERICAL-CYLINDRICAL TRANSFORMATIONS AND ON DIRECTIONAL EFFECTS, handwritten and typed (Box 5, Folder 63)
- ELECTROMETER REPRINTS (Box 5, Folder 64)
  correspondence between Hansen and W. Mansfield Clark of Johns Hopkins School of Medicine dated 1937, plus handwritten material
- CALCULATIONS FOR GRAPHS (Box 5, Folder 65)
  various graphs and data sheets
- ABERRATIONS IN ELECTRON LENSES (Box 5, Folder 66)
  handwritten and one graph
- CALCULATION OF MONOTRON SHAPES (Box 5, Folder 67)
  various graphs, data sheets, etc.
- NO TITLE (Box 5, Folder 68[R-8])
  unidentified handwritten materials, appears to be in connection with airplane landing control, radar or similar
- EXPLORATORTY CALCULATIONS ON SPHERICAL EARTH PROBLEM (Box 5, Folder 69)
  handwritten material plus some graphs, some material on "Antenna Practice" etc., 1938
- VECTOR EXPANSION OF e-ikr 12/r 12 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  mostly at M.I.T. start of rhumbatron, 1933 (includes reject of Hansen article submitted for publication to The Physical Review, Reviews of Modern Physics, and Physics [all the same] entitled: "A New Type of Expansion", plus various handwritten material
- RHUMBATRON CALCULATIONS (Box 5, Folder 71)
  various typed and handwritten material
- MONOTRON MS (Box 5, Folder 72)
  typed abstract: "On A Simplified Short Wave Oscillator" by Hansen and Russell Harrison Varian & original handwritten
- BEGINNING ON MONOTRON (Box 6, Folder 73[M-3])
  various handwritten material, graphs, dated 1937
- RHUMBATRON PAPER PRESENTED TO AMERICAN PHYSICAL SOCIETY, June, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 74[C-6])
  typed and handwritten material and various graphs
- KLYSTRON EFFICIENCY (Box 6, Folder 75[K-2])
  graphs and handwritten material dated 1937
- RHUMBATRON PAPER WITH HOLLINGSWORTH (Box 6, Folder 76[C-12])
  typed preliminary draft, some graphs and drawings
- RHUMBATRON AS A RESONATOR, MS TO INSTITUTE OF RADIO ENGINEERS (Box 6, Folder 77[C-14])
  correspondence with I.R.E. about publication of article entitled: includes drawings, calculations and short biographical note for publisher
- "CURRENT-VOLTAGE-EFFICIENCY CHARACTERISTIC CURVES FOR KLYSTRON OSCILLATORS", handwritten abstract and 3 typed copies (Box 6, Folder 78[K-6])
- HANSEN-VARIAN AMPLIFIER (Box 6, Folder 79[I-13])
  research notes for Spring, 1930, article from Radio News February, 1930 entitled: "The Amplifier Steps Out"; various graphs; a letter of correspondence with Sangamo Electric Co. about a certain type of condensor
- RESONANCE FREQUENCY CLOSED LINE (Box 6, Folder 80[K-8])
  various handwritten material dated 1938, reply to Hansen's request for booklet on publishing form from American Institute of Physics
- "VERY ROUGH CALCULATIONS ON SELF BUNCHERS", handwritten (Box 6, Folder 81[K-7])
- SMOOTHING CIRCUITS (Box 6, Folder 82[E-1])
  handwritten material and graphs
- "DESIGN OF A SHAKER TRACK" (Box 6, Folder 83[P-14])
  handwritten material and many graphs
- QUARTER WAVE LINE (Box 6, Folder 84[C-16])
  "On the Resonant Frequency of Closed Concentric Lines", typewritten; "Numerical Example and Estimate of Errors", handwritten; several sheets of calculations
- "CAUSES OF FREQUENCY VARIATION IN KLYSTRON OSCILLATORS", typed MS (Box 6, Folder 85[K-3])
- RADIATION THROUGH HOLES (Box 7, Folder 86[C-15])
  handwritten, entitled: "Calculations for Rand Press Filter and Antenna"; other material dated 1937 and 1938
- CIRCULAR FLOATING ONE (Box 7, Folder 87[K-5])
  handwritten, graphs and calculations
- "ON THE ACCELERATION OF CHARGED PARTICLES BY OSCILLATING FIELDS BOUNDED BY GRIDS" (Box 7, Folder 88[K-4])
  handwritten abstract and typed copy, several graphs
- "ON THE ABSOLUTE DETERMINATION OF ELECTRICAL UNITS" (Box 7, Folder 89[P-13])
  abstract of article supposedly published in American Journal of Physics in late 1930s; "Measurement of Current", handwritten abstract and copy; graphs, drawings and etc.
- MICROMANIPULATOR PAPER WITH SOME DRAWINGS (Box 7, Folder 90[I-10])
  typed paper, purchase orders for parts, folder on Zeiss Micromanipulators, some handwritten material
- "ON BAND PASS FILTERS USING RHUMBATRONS", handwritten abstract with typed copy (Box 7, Folder 91[C-13])
- INSTITUTE OF RADIO ENGINEERS RADAR PAPER FIGURES (Box 7, Folder 92)
  various drawings, graphs, etc. presumably as indicated by title
- "CONCERNING NEW METHODS OF CALCULATION RADIATION RESISTANCE, EITHER WITH OR WITHOUT GROUND" (Box 7, Folder 93[R-10])
  typed paper and note that it formed the basis of a talk to joint meeting of I.R.E. and American section of U.R.S.I. in Washington D.C. May, 1936; other material and letter to editor of proceedings of I.R.E., dated 1936
- RADIATION THEORY (Box 7, Folder 94[R-11])
  handwritten, graphs and drafts
- RADIATION THEORY (Box 7, Folder 95[R-12])
  notes taken to Washington (typed and handwritten) for U.R.S.I. program in April and May, 1936
- "DESIGN OF FLAT SHOOTING ANTENNA ARRAYS" BY HANSEN AND HOLLINGSWORTH, Spring 1938 (Box 7, Folder 96[R-13])
  typed article and handwritten copy, much other material
- FIELD AT GROUND: CHASING OUT ERRORS (Box 7, Folder 97[R-14])
  also typed abstract entitled: "Directional Characteristics of Any Antenna Over a Plane Earth", and 2 copies; handwritten material; article by Hollingsworth entitled: "Report on Radiation Theory and Summerfield Theory"; translation of a German article
- NUMERICAL CALCULATIONS FOR FIRST I.R.E. PAPER (Box 8, Folder 98[R-15])
  with original copy of table three; handwritten and typed material, some of handwritten entitled: "Vertical Quarter Wave Antenna With Ground"; graphs, drawings and calculations
- "RADIATION FROM ARBITRARY ANTENNA OVER AN EARTH OF FINITE CONDUCTIVITY" (Box 8, Folder 99[R-16])
  typed and handwritten copies of MS for first paper in Physics
- "PROBABILITIES OF K-ELECTRON IONIZATION OF SILVER BY CATHODE RAYS" (Box 8, Folder 100[P-9])
  MS for paper with Stoddard on line and continuous radiation; also handwritten and typed material including a description of an experiment by Hansen and Stoddard
- TERMAN'S PROBLEM ON REFLECTIONS FROM THE IONOSPHERE (Box 8, Folder 101[P-10])
  typed and handwritten material; letter from H.. Westman, secretary of the I.R.E. re: publication of an article on this work
- KIRKPATRICK'S SHOTPUT CORRECTION (Box 8, Folder 102[P-11])
  handwritten material, calculations, etc.; typed reference attached and signed P K (possibly Paul Harmon Kirkpatrick)
- "J" PHENOMENON (Box 8, Folder 103[P-12])
  handwritten data sheets, several sheets entitled: "Superposition of X-rays" by Gerald L. Pearson and W.W. Hansen
- HADLEY REPORT -"Report on Klystron Amplifier Measurements" by Charles F. Hadley, June 30, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 104[K-1])
- "CALCULATIONS OF THE TOTAL RADIATION FROM ACCELERATED RAPIDLY MOVING ELECTRONS", handwritten (Box 8, Folder 105[P-8])
- MEASURE OF TRANSIENT RESPONSE OF AMPLIFIERS (Box 8, Folder 106-107[I-9])
  handwritten, partial title, c. 89 pp (?80); other handwritten material and graphs; originally one unidentified folder, divided into two because of volume
- COMPUTATIONS FOR WOODYARD (Box 8, Folder 108)
  handwritten, graphs, data sheets, etc., undated
- RADIATION THEORY (Box 8, Folder l09[P-8])
  mostly at M.I.T. and Michigan; handwritten, calculations, graphs, data sheets, etc.
- "ON THE CHARACTERISTICS OF A CERTAIN SHAPE OF RESONATOR" (Box 8, Folder 110[C-10])
  handwritten with copy; data sheets, graphs, etc., some dated 1939
- FREQUENCY OF RESONANT CAVITIES (Box 9, Folder 111[C-9])
  handwritten entitled: "Magnetic Field with Cylindrical Symmetry"; data sheets, graphs, etc.; most dated June, 1941
- DETAILED CALCULATIONS ON ENERGY LOSS ON REFLECTION -, undated; handwritten (Box 9, Folder 112[C-8])
- UNPUBLISHED PAPERS (Box 9, Folder 113[C-7a,b,c,d])
  typed; abstract with drawings: "On Band Pass Filters Using Rhumbatrons"; abstract, December, 1937: "On Radiative Rhumbatrons"; MS with graph: "Dielectric Rhumbatrons"; MS, 25 pp.,: "A Type of Electrical Resonator"
- LIST OF PUBLISHED PAPERS -prepared by F. Black for National Academy of Science, handwritten (Box 9, Folder 114)
- CALCULATIONS & MS FOR "PHYSICS" RHUMBATRON, handwritten (Box 9, Folder ll5)
- KINEMATIC DESIGN DRAWINGS (Box 9, Folder 116)
  various drawings, some with notations by Hansen
- ELECTROSTATIC FOCUSING AT RELATIVISTIC SPEEDS, typed, one copy in English, one in French (Box 9, Folder 117)
- "DIELECTRIC LOSSES OF VARIOUS CONCENTRIC CABLES AT 3000 Mc" by William W. Hansen and Charles H. Pope (Box 9, Folder 118)
  2 copies, typed or mimeographed, paper bears imprint of Sperry Gyroscope Co.
- TUBE OPERATING POINTS -, March 12, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  interoffice memo by Hansen at Sperry Gyroscope Co., apparently a report with 2 graphs
- MICROWAVE INTENSITY NOMOGRAPHS, May 21, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 120)
  inter-office memo (mimeographed copy) with graph-data sheets
- REPORT ON KLYSTRON AMPLIFIER MEASUREMENTS. by Charles F. Hadley, December 29, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 121)
  mimeographed, 23 pp with several data sheets; submitted to Sperry Gyroscope Co.
- END-FIRE WAVE GUIDE RADIATORS, December 3, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 122)
  inter-office memo from M.H. Johnson to R.L. Wathen and W.H. Ratliff (?); typed
- RECTIFICATION TEST, January 16, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 123)
  Sperry Gyroscope Co. inter-office memo from M.H. Johnson and C.H. Pope to Hansen; typed.
- SPHERICAL-CYLINDRICAL TRANSFORMATIONS (Box 9, Folder 124)
  1 handwritten and 2 typed copies of abstract: "Transformations Useful in Certain Antenna Calculations"; correspondence relating to its publication in Journal of Applied Physics including galley proof and notification of intent to publish in April, 1937 issue.
- VALUES OF P FUNCTIONS, handwritten data sheets (Box 9, Folder 125)
- TABLE OF ei(x) (Box 9, Folder 126)
  mimeographed, notation, interpolated by Hansen from Glaisher's Tables; material relating to Physics 25, Spring, 1930 and1931 entitled: "Comparison of Electrons and Light"
- "ON THE RESONANT FREQUENCY OF CLOSED CONCENTRIC LINES" (Box 9, Folder 127)
  handwritten with 2 typed copies; correspondence relating to publication in Journal of Applied Physics, Aug. 5, 1938; graphs and one handwritten sheet of calculations (apparently corrections in the article).
- MATERIAL RELATING TO HANSEN'S STUDIES AT STANFORD AS A STUDENT
  - NOTES ON WAVE MECHANICS AND ETC. (Box 9, Folder 128)
    handwritten and undated (although could be 1930 or '31), cover diverse subjects such as and including Heisenberg matrix elements.
  - NOTES ON PHYSICS 183, Winter 1931-'32 (Box 9, Folder 129)
    most are carbons, author unknown, handwritten; some typed, author unknown; handwritten, problem sets, etc.
  - SUMMARY OF PHYSICS 123, typed, notation on front cover: not to be removed from the LIBRARY (Box 9, Folder 130)
  - NOTES ON PHYSICS 123 (Box 9, Folder 131)
    appears to be a duplication of folder 129 except problem sets and leading page indicating they belong to Hansen
  - PROBLEMS FOR PHYSICS 125, Spring, 1934-35 (Box 10, Folder 132)
    also some handwritten material designated as problems [note: these are not solutions]; possibly material Hansen may have used an a teaching assistant; unidentified and undated.
  - "BOUNDARY WAVE PROBLEMS" (Box 10, Folder 133)
    handwritten, unidentified and undated, appears to be Hansen's handwriting
- MISCELLANEOUS
  - Work done by L.H. Franklin (student) for Hansen, includes various loose sheets and diagrams (Box 10, Folder 134)
  - Various graphs, data sheets, etc., apparently done by Beckerley in, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 135)
  - Various unrelated handwritten calculations, data sheets, etc., undated and unclassified (Box 10, Folder 136)
  - Graphs, most done in, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 137)
  - Handwritten calculations etc., 1940-47 (Box 10, Folder 138)
  - Various handwritten and typed sheets, one entitled: "Velocity of Light" (Box 10, Folder 139)
  - Calculations, graphs., etc. (Box 10, Folder 140)
  - Report for Hansen's Physics 250 by T.E. Veltfort (student), completed, Dec. 13, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 141)
  - Various typed reports apparently by Hansen; includes "10 cm Signal Generator" & "A New Type of Variable Stroke Pump", etc. (Box 10, Folder 142)
- FORD "A" MOTOR (Box 10, Folder 143)
  various references to one of Hansen's cars and other things of automotive nature, dated early 1930s.
- SPHERE DRAWINGS (Box 10, Folder 144)
  various drawings, calculations, etc.
- W.W. HANSEN MISCELLANEOUS UNSORTED MATERIAL (Box 10, Folder 145)
  includes personal correspondence and other unsorted material
- "AN INFORMAL REPORT ON KLYSTRON RESEARCH SINCE LAST SPRING" (Box 11, Folder 146[K-11])
  letter from Hansen to D.L. Webster, 16 typed pages and several photographs
- KLYSTRONICS LECTURE NOTES, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 147[K-9A])
- "KLYSTRON KLASS", 1940 (Box 11, Folder 148[K-9A])
  handwritten, dated for fall, 1940, property of Hansen
- KLYSTRONICS, M.I.T., 1941 (Box 11, Folder 149[K-9B])
- RHUMBATRONICS, M.I.T., 1941; handwritten, 6 pages (Box 11, Folder 150)
- DISPERSION OF GLASS (Box 11, Folder 151)
  mimeographed experiment sheet for Physics 152, Autumn, 1935-36; with 5 copies
- OLD EXPERIMENTS (Box 11, Folder 152)
  for Physics 152 and 154, most for year 1935-36, some for 1941-42, all mimeographed or copied; and "Experiment IV. Wave-Length Measurement with the Michelson Interferometer" for Physics 152
- PHYSICS 152, EXPERIMENTS l, 3, 4, 7, 8, AND 9, 1946.; copies, some with notations (Box 11, Folder 153)
- PHYSICS 152, 153, and 154 EXPERIMENT SHEETS, 1947-48; all mimeographed, many with handwritten notations. (Box 11, Folder 154)
- MODERN PHYSICS LAB, AUTUMN, 1936-37 (Box 11, Folder 155)
  copies of all experiments; rough draft of article "An Apparatus for the Determination of the Gravitation Constant", Jan., 1936; personal correspondence with RCA Co. re: cathode ray tubes, 1937; data sheets etc.; reprint of article by Hansen and Lundstrom from Proceedings of the I.R.E. Vol. 33, No. 8, August, 1945, entitled: "Experimental Determination of Impedance Functions by the Use... "; much handwritten material; copy of patent by Harry Nyquist (Patent Office No. 1,915,440; issued in 1933)
- "AIR TRAFFIC CONTROL ANTENNA" (Box 11, Folder 156)
  handwritten, appears to be Hansen's, possibly experiment notes, 21 pages
- W.W. HANSEN, ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING DEPT., M.I.T. 0N SPERRYGYRO, GARDEN CITY (Box 11, Folder 157[E-3])
  handwritten notes, calculations, etc.
- W.W. HANSEN, RADIATION LAB, U.C. (Box 11, Folder 158[E-6])
  handwritten notes, calculations, 37 pages
- "NUCLEAR DISPERSION" (Box 11, Folder 159)
  notebook and 2 loose sheets, handwritten notes, calculations, graphs, etc., title page dated Aug. 29, 1945
- LAB BOOK, NO TITLE, handwritten, first 18 pages missing (Box 11, Folder 160[I-11])
- TRANSIENT RESPONSE OF WIDEBAND AMPLIFIERS, in three spiral notebooks (Box 12, Folder 161[E-2A,B,C])
- KLYSTRONICS, M.I.T., 1941, handwritten (Box 12, Folder 162[K-9B])
- W.W. HANSEN, ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING DEPT., M.I.T. or SPERRY GYRO, GARDEN CITY, [Book 1]; W.W. HANSEN, RADIATION LAB, M.I.T. or SPERRY GYRO [Books 2-6], handwritten (Box 12, Folder 163[P-15])
- A.A. COMPUTER, VOLS. II and III (Box 12, Folder 164[E4A,B])
  handwritten, entitled: "Generalities Relative to Electronic Computers", also loose drawings and calculations
- NO TITLE -handwritten, some sheets dated, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 165[C-17])
- W.W. HANSEN, RADIATION LAB, M.I.T. or SPERRY GYRO, GARDEN CITY [Book 8], handwritten (Box 13, Folder 166[P-15])
- NO TITLE -three handwritten notebooks dated, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 167[K-10A,B,C])